Gael Turnbull Papers
© 2005 University of Connecticut
Gael Turnbull Papers.
undated, 1965-1973.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Center.
Turnbull, Gael.
.10 linear feet.
Gael Turnbull was born 7 April 1928, in Edinburgh, Scotland. He attended Cambridge University (B.A., 1948) and the University of Pennsylvania (M.D., 1951). Awarded the Union League Civic and Arts Foundation Prize (1965) and Alice Hunt Bartlett Prize (1968), Turnbull has been a Physician in general practice and anesthesiologist in Worcestershire, England, since 1951. His poetry has been published since 1954.
MSS19980216
Biography
Gael Turnbull was born 7 April 1928, in Edinburgh, Scotland, the son of Ralph Gale (a minister) and Anne (Lundin) Turnbull. He attended Cambridge University (B.A., 1948) and the University of Pennsylvania (M.D., 1951). Awarded the Union League Civic and Arts Foundation Prize (1965) and Alice Hunt Bartlett Prize (1968), Turnbull has been a Physician in general practice and anesthesiologist in Worcestershire, England, since 1951. His poetry has been published since 1954.
Writings by the Author:
Poem
(With Eli Mandel and Phyllis Webb) Trio, Contact Press (Toronto), 1954.
The Knot in the Wood and Fifteen Other Poems, Revision Press (London), 1955.
Bjarni Spike-Helgi's Son and Other Poems, Origin Press (Ashland, Mass.), 1956.
A Libation, The Poet (Glasgow), 1957.
With Hey, Ho...., Migrant Press (Birmingham, England), 1961.
To You, I Write, Migrant Press, 1963.
A Very Particular Hill, Wild Hawthorn Press, 1963.
Twenty Words, Twenty Days: A Sketchbook and a Morula, Migrant Press, 1966.
Briefly, Tarasque Press (Nottingham, England), 1967.
A Trampoline: Poems 1952-1964, Cape Goliard Press, 1968.
I Maksoud, University of Exeter, 1969.
Scantlings: Poems 1964-69, Cape Goliard Press, 1970.
Finger Cymbals, Satis (Edinburgh), 1972.
A Random Sampling, Pig Press (New castle-upon-Tyne, England), 1974.
Wulstan, Blue Tunnel (Bradford England), 1975.
Witley Court Revisited, Migrant Press, 1975.
Residues, Grosseteste (Staffordshire, England), 1976.
Thronging the Heart, Aggie Weston, 1976.
If a Glance Could Be Enough, Satis, 1978.
Rain in Wales, Satis, 1981.
A Gathering of Poems, 1950-1980 (a retrospective collected edition of earlier work), Anvil Press (London), 1983.
(With John Christie) Nine Intersections, Circle Press (Guildford), 1982.
Source: Contemporary Authors Online. The Gale Group, 1999.
Scope and Content
Letters of Turnbull to Melville Hardiment on personal and literary matters. The collection also includes a few poems and an essay on Basil Bunting (cf. 17 January 1965).
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of literary materials. See especially, papers of Larry Eigner, Charles Olson and Tom Raworth. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Bibliography
Poets of Great Britain and Ireland Since 1880. Dictionary of Literary Biography v. 40. Detroit: Gale, 1985.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Bunting, Basil.
Subjects:
British literature—20th century.; Poets, English—20th century.; Great Britain—Cultural affairs—Literature.; Essays.; Poems.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Manuscripts.
Occupations:
Physician. Poet.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
Provenance unknown. Probable purchase
Detailed Description
- Series I: Papers, undated, 1965-1973
  - undated, 1965 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - 1966 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - 1967 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - 1968 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - 1969 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - 1970 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - 1971 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - 1972 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - 1973 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - “The Real McCoy” playbill, 1972 (Box 1:, Folder 10)